Paalamugan S

Senior Software Engineer - Full Stack



Personal details

Name Paalamugan S

Email address developer@paalamugan .com

Phone number +918838782493

Website paalamugan.com

Certificationspaalamugan.com/certifications

LinkedInlinkedin.com/in/paalam
ugan-s-a6baa315b

GitHub github.com/paalamugan

Profile

Having **6+ years** of experience in **FullStack development** and more enthusiasm for my work. Extensive experience in working with **Product development** and strong skill sets in both **Front-End** and **Back-End development**.

Skills

Frontend Development - HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, NextJs, React, Redux, Angular, Vue, Svelte, GatsBy, Styled-Components, Chrome Extension.

Backend Development - Nodejs, Express, REST API, Graphql, Jest, Mocha, Cypress, Mongodb, Mysql, Redis, Sequelize, Prisma, RabbitMq, PubSub.

Devops Development - Git, Jenkins, CI/CD, GitHub Actions, Hosting, Networking, Google Cloud Platform, Distributed System, Amazon EC2, Amazon S3, Docker, Kubernetes, SonarQube, Synk.

Full Stack Development - MERN Stack, MEAN Stack, JAM Stack, Remix.

Operating System - Linux(Ubuntu), MacOS, Windows

Achievements

Own Website Development:

I developed my website from scratch using **NextJS** Framework with **100% covering** all software standard levels.

<u>Click Here</u> to see the screenshot of my website performance from the **chrome developer tool(lighthouse) survey**. Hard work and **passion** for coding gave me **good learning** and **encouraged me** to do much better.

If you're interested, You can also check out my website here. https://paalamugan.com

NPM Package:

I Published 3 npm packages to the npm registry to make the developer's work easy when they will working using a single-spa micro frontend with React framework.

- https://www.npmjs.com/package/@single-spa-example/react-styleguide
- https://www.npmjs.com/package/@single-spa-example/global
- https://www.npmjs.com/package/@single-spa-example/config

Employment

Senior Software Engineer - Full Stack

Aug 2021 - Present

Quantiphi Analytics Solution, Bangalore

- Working as a FullStack developer with Angular, Reactjs, Nextjs, and Nodejs Frameworks. Especially I'm working with Typescript Language on top of all frameworks.
- Currently I work for a Maersk client, In the current project, We have been using NextJs with TypeScript framework and Redux for State management in the Micro frontend and Nodejs with Express, TypeScript, and Prisma for relational database connection and Helmet NPM Package for API Security in the Micro service's backend.
- In the current project, We are using @testing-library/react, Jest, Mocha, Chai, and Cypress for TDD.
- Had worked with clients such as Arizona Health Care Cost Containment System (AHCCCS), and General Motors-USA.
- Worked with React for Arizona Health Care Cost Containment System (AHCCCS) Project.
- Implemented **AHCCCS** Internal Admin UI using **React** with **TypeScript** framework.
- Worked with Angular12, NodeJs, Express, Typescript, and PubSub for General Motors-USA Project.
- Created a Backend Server using Express with TypeScript from scratch as per the client's requirement.
- Developed showing all conversations and session listing UI page in frontend using Angular with TypeScript framework.
- Implemented some of the **Dialogflow Messenger** chatbot functionality that doesn't support by **Dialogflow**.
- I played around with **HTML dom-manipulation** using **Javascript** as per client need.
- Implemented additional functionality like Refresh,

- **Language Switch,** and **FullScreen** buttons in the **Dialogflow Messenger** chatbot.
- Created custom **webpack** configuration especially for that project to the minified bundle of all the script files.

Software Engineer

Dec 2018 - Jul 2021

NamLabs Technologies Pvt Ltd, Chennai

- Had Worked as a Full stack web developer at **NamLabs Sass Based Product** Company.
- It owns 4 Products such as Atatus, UI Inspector, ReplayBird, and LeadMine.
- Literally I get a chance to work with all the products that I mentioned above.
- Worked extensively on Typescript, Angular, React, Redux, GatsBy, Vue, Jest, and Mocha Framework in frontend development and NodeJS with Express, Python with Flask in backend development.
- Worked with both Relational(Mysql, Clickhouse) and Non-Relational(Mongodb, Redis, Meilisearch) Databases.
- Able to develop the design and implementation for the application independently from scratch.

Atatus Product:

- Developed full Layout module for atatus documentation page using Jekyll(Static Site Generator) tool.
- Six main features of atatus product, Literally I gave my contribution around 4 features, Feature name called Application Performance Monitoring, Browser Monitoring, Infrastructure Monitoring, and Synthetic Monitor.
- Implemented Most of the functionality in the Synthetic monitor feature both Frontend(Angular) and backend (NodeJs). It includes web monitors, DNS monitoring, SSL monitoring, and TCP monitoring.

ReplayBird Product:

 Developed a Full Static website for end-to-end individually using GatsBy(ReactJs and Redux) with Typescript and Graphql Framework.

Lead Mine Product:

 Implemented storing credit/debit card details information powered by Stripe(Payment Tools) and developed a subscription page using Vue Framework with Typescript.

UI Inspector Product:

- Had been Worked on most of the features for this product development both **front end and back end**.
- Developed Dashboard Page, Testcase Page, and Plan Page in both front end and back end using Angular, MongoDB, and NodeJS with Typescript.
- Done test run in **Cron Server** every 5min, 10min, and 1 hour and put some entry in **Redis** to check the status is passed or failed.
- Build custom **chrome extension** tools to help the user action in the record and save it to **MongoDB**.
- Record the user action with the help of **chrome extension** tools and run the test with a specific plan.

Junior Software Engineer

May 2018 - Nov 2018

Add-on Technology, Chennai

- Had been worked as a MEAN stack developer where I implemented Bakery internal Product(Anumod Bakery) using MEAN stack technology(MongoDB, Express, Angular, NodeJs).
- Created the bakery application from scratch using Angular
 6 with Typescript on the frontend side, and NODEJS with Typescript, and Express in the backend.
- Implemented a Solution for Sending Messages to the customer about the order detail using **nodemailer**.
- Developed Small E-commerce Project using Reactjs with TypeScript, Redux for State management, and Material-UI framework.
- On that E-Commerce project, I implemented CRUD API for products list in NodeJS with Express, Typescript, Sequelize(MYSQL) npm Package.

Software Developer

Aug 2017 - Apr 2018

Muthu Soft Labs, Chennai

- Had worked as a Software developer at Muthu Soft Labs and learned HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, Angular, Nodejs, and Photoshop.
- Worked on an internal project called tangedco using Angular and Nodejs Framework.
- Developed UX Design for FinePaperSource Project using Photoshop.

Education

B.E - ECE

Jun 2013 - Apr 2017

P.B College Of Engineering, Chennai

Studied an Electronics and Communication Engineering